i believe i've mentioned it a couple
times before but maybe
not on here i joined this facebook group
that talks about climate change being
limbic
problems the limbic system in our brain
and when i read
what the limbic system does i know it's
a lot of the issues i have a problem
with
i have a neurodiverse brain i've had a
d and known about it most of my life and
i have autism but only discovered that i
had that even though i had it my whole
life i only discovered that i had it a
couple years ago
and then i also had brain surgery
and radiation on my brain which together
resulted
in a mild tbi with my brains falling
after my first surgery and the radiation
and all of the changes um i just anyway
so
in the facebook group the main guy who
is a neuroscientist
posted he posts a lot of stuff that
triggers me because he
even just the fact that and it's not him
who calls himself an act like he calls
himself an expert because he's a
neuroscientist i think
most people in the world would agree
with that
but i don't i don't think you can be an
expert in something without experiencing
it and you only have one brain to
experience
and the issue with being an expert in
the brain and thinking you have the
answers and yet only having access to
one brain
is it's the definite place where experts
end up hurting you instead of helping
you
because they think they're the expert
okay but he posted this 20 minute video
linked it in the description which i
actually found was very powerful and i
don't know who the doctor is in it
um but the doctor is very thorough and
he's exactly the kind of specialist you
would want to see
for a mild tbi which he talks in there
is is um
one of the most devastating things that
someone can have and a lot of times they
go undiagnosed
because we don't know their brains have
been injured we've gotten hit we've
gotten in a fight we've got we've gotten
in a minor accident
and um traumatic brain injuries are
they change your brain even mild ones
and so talking to this this guy who he's
he's doing
the brains kind of they have a colorful
brain scan i don't know what they're
called but i've had dozens of mris
and they've never given me a colorful
one
um which is he also talks about how in
our medical system
we have divorced the brain and the mind
with neuroscientists taking over the
brain
and psychiatrists taking over the mind
and this is part of the problem
i've had in the medical system is it
somewhat like experts in software and
experts in hardware when you go to the
experts in hardware they blame it on the
software
they blame it they're like yes this is
the part that's my hardware and you need
to do
steps x y and z and if they're not
working it's because it's the other the
other system
and so each expert both tells you to do
things that will
help that part the mind or the brain
without ever taking into consideration
the other piece
and you're made to feel wrong about it
constantly if it's not working for you
you're the problem right if you can't
change your thoughts you're the problem
if your brain
if your brain is having issues but we
can't see it physically on a scan
that's a problem and that's also even
just looking at the brain
these colorful mri images are your brain
in your mind
it's your brain working as a mind it's
you thinking it's lighting up the
different areas based on emotion
based on activity based on all these
things you can see if your brain is
healthy
if you're what your brain looks like
compared to other people's
um i wish everyone had access to a
doctor like this
and at the same time i know nobody does
and so going asking people to go to
experts when they're never going to get
this kind of treatment
um and even with this treatment i
imagine this doctor is a very expensive
doctor to go and see
plus the things that he says fish oil i
try to take the soil but it's hard to
remember to take it
and it's like okay put a thing in your
phone right then i'm going to ignore it
it's like in order to be able to repair
your brain you have to be able to repair
your brain
and that's that's part of it but i know
for me if my biggest priority was taking
um
fish oil i would manage to do it so that
is going to become one of my biggest
priorities
i also talked about keeping a journal
which i find helpful
just kind of saying what what has
happened that day whether you felt
yourself
positive negative but he does talk about
having a list of everything that you
you want out of life like out of your
which i'm kind of doing in a six week
course
but we'll be doing it together but
there's also
like to ask are my actions helping with
that every day
no but i can't do the actions that help
with it like so it's not
really helping it's like okay if taking
the fish oil is going to help but you
can't remember to take the fish oil
that's a problem and then
some of the other things he suggested um
are alternative therapies
that are highly expensive and not
accessible hyperbaric oxygen chamber
um acupuncture which i've tried and
hasn't worked for anything
um and um infrared sauna all of which
are expensive especially if you
have to do 50 to 100 sessions to repair
your brain
right which is like right but if my
brains aren't repaired i probably don't
have a great job
and this is the issue with most medical
problems especially brain ones
is all my medical problems anyway is
it's all
um chicken and egg it's like if my house
is clean i do better but keeping my
house clean cost me all my spoons
if my brain was healthier i'd be able to
do the things to keep it healthy and so
this
part of my frustration is this
focus on healing your brain instead of a
focus on accepting your brain
because anyone can kind of accept their
brain
not everyone can heal their brain can
your brain heal yes brains can heal
but not everyone's can heal not everyone
can heal to the same
degree so even if a hundred people get
this exact same traumatic brain injury
and they all go through the exact same
program
not all of them are gonna heal and so to
say okay well someone else had your
brain injury and they healed doesn't
mean you're going to and yet belief in
the healing system
helps it work and when you've been
through enough treatments that haven't
worked you have less and less belief in
the new ones for me
i know i'm like unless it's free unless
it's guaranteed i'm not doing it
but watching this i was he does have
some techniques some thought techniques
that were um like the negative thoughts
in your head is this true
am i 100 certain this is true how do i
feel about it being true and one of the
powerful things he talks about is
flipping it around
and not just there was three ways to
flip it around the guys
um and i'm not remember what the three
are just tell
but they're flipping around completely
so like i'm stupid could be unsmart
um but then sometimes it's it's flipping
it so i think you're stupid
might be the negative thought in my head
that's causing me negative emotion so i
can flip it around to say i'm stupid i
can flip it around to say
you're smart and i can flip it around to
say
it's like my anyway there's three ways
to to do the opposite
it was like say the actual opposite of
the sentence flip it so it's about you
and um flip it so it's not about you i
think this is the third one something
like that
something like that changing the verb
something along those lines
but there's i find frustration because
i the more i try to heal my brain
the worse it becomes and the more i
accept it as it is the more
it's helping me create a world that
works for everyone so i live in a very
unique
position and i am an expert in my brain
no one else can be an expert in my brain
it has been cut open it has been
radiated it has been has so many
pictures of it
and yet unless there is an expert like
this expert in this video
and even then i'm gonna i'm gonna come
to that with all of my baggage
right and it's like to think that you
can go to an expert
and get this level of treatment he's one
in a million
because of what he talks about we have
have separated
the mind and the brain if you go to one
expert they are not an expert in the
other one and they pass everything they
want to pass off to the other one
like i said it's like going to a
hardware doctor and then blaming
everything on the software and going to
a software doctor and blaming everything
on the hardware
and making you respond you're the one to
pick the software you can change it if
you wanted
the hardware doesn't look like it has a
problem so it's got to be the software
and i'm the hardware person go to them
and they don't communicate and they
don't coordinate and then the patient's
supposed to be able to do that go to the
psychiatrist to get
mind help and go to the neurologist to
get brain help
and you're supposed to be able to put
the two together which is nearly
impossible for anyone especially someone
who some brain for issues
so i'm in this group because it keeps
triggering me and i know i'm like yep
here's my learning and
to bring my expertise to it even if they
don't see my expertise as expertise
i don't think you can be an expertise in
an animal unless you've lived in that
animal's body
you can't you can never be a frog expert
a chimpanzee expert an elephant expert
unless you know how to mind meld and be
one
because you can dissect it
you can learn about it you could see its
behaviors
and and make um inferences about that
but you're never going to be an elephant
expert or a chimpanzee expert
or a frog expert and lets you live as
one
and those things don't go together
similar with brains right they can never
you can never live in another person's
body
so you can never be an expert in their
brain but i can tell you having a brain
that is different and a brain that has
changed
that is one of my superpowers because i
can see the world in different ways
i remember before i knew before my tbi
during my tbi after my first surgery
when i i
experienced my brain swelling and was
acting like a toddler
and having these tender tantrums of like
there's too much sound and too much
light and too much spells
and stop it like why can't you all just
stop it
um but not being able to even verbally
communicate that made me have so much
more empathy for my child when she was
going through that stage
going through that stage of like the
world's not working for me and i have no
power over it
and i know that the day i go through
having patients and a brain that works
in the morning and having less patience
and being non-verbal and not being able
to do things in the evening
helps me have more patience overall and
so
my belief is that our brain diversity
is exactly what it's supposed to be and
the individual can
seek out to heal their brain but their
brain is only going to heal as much as
it's supposed to and making them wrong
for it in any way making them wrong for
accepting their brain making them wrong
for having
a brain injury and making them wrong for
not being able to heal or not wanting to
heal
all of it it's like we're exactly who
we're supposed to be i know i am
i can't imagine what my brain would
would be what i would be giving the
world if i didn't have my brain tumors i
didn't have
my neurodiversity that i was born with
which still could have
i could have done a lot of what i'm
doing i don't know because it
is this different the brain change not
just being different
but the actual experience of
experiencing my neuro diverse brain
before
tbi and after and during and all of that
has given me any experience i'd say
the one person i might give expertise to
besides this doctor who does seem to be
an expert in both the mind and the brain
and i would probably hand over some of
my intellectual sovereignty for him to
make decisions
but also with the help of right but i
can't do it foreign
but the other person i don't remember
her name which has a ted talk or the
i think they're a neurosurgeon or a
neurologist who goes through having a
stroke
and i'm like yep that person i will give
brain expert
to because they've experienced it but
most people in the medical profession
they might be neurodiverse they might
have autism they might have add but if
they do they don't have it harsh because
they've gone through medical school
they got into university they went
through medical school they figured out
how to get over their wall of yogurt
they figured out how to study how to do
it with or without adrenaline
whereas most people who've gone through
having anxiety having depression having
add having
autism don't get into med school
and if they do they don't make it
through and so the ones that we want
there to be the experts aren't there
and so we're dealing with a bunch of
neurotypical at least not tbi people who
are like telling people
tbis how it should be for them because
they studied in a textbook
instead of experiencing it so i just
want to come on here
suggest watching the video in the
description because it is an amazing one
and i will see you next time